Finding Aid for the Edouard Roditi Papers LSC.0644
UCLA Library Special Collections
Edouard Roditi papers
1910-1992
UCLA Library Special Collections
Roditi, Edouard
LSC.0644
90 Linear Feet (174 boxes, 12 oversize boxes, and 1 oversize folder)
Edouard Roditi (1910-1992) was a surrealist author and poet. He published the first Surrealist manifesto in English, "The new reality," in the Oxford outlook (1929). While continuing his literary interests, he worked for the U.S. government during World War II for the Office of War Information and also served as an interpreter for the State Department during the San Francisco conference which established the United Nations. His published books include Poems for F (1934), Oscar Wilde: a critical study (1947), Dialogues on art (1960), De l'homosexualité (1962), In a lost world (1978), and Thrice chosen (1981). Roditi also held teaching positions at various colleges and universities. The collection consists of material related to Roditi's life and career. Includes correspondence, original and photocopied manuscripts by Roditi and others, books, periodicals and other printed items by or about Roditi, documents, awards, photographs, memorabilia, and letters regarding family history and biographical information, and books from his library, including many inscribed by artists and writers.
Restrictions on Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Provenance/Source of Acquisition
Gift of Edouard Roditi, 1967-1991.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942336803606533
Biography
Édouard Roditi was born in Paris, June 6, 1910; he was educated in England at Elstree, Charterhouse, and Balliol, and received a BA from the University of Chicago; he became acquainted with T.S. Eliot, James Joyce, André Breton and other leading literary figures, while living in London, Paris, and Berlin (1929-37); he published the first Surrealist manifesto in English, "The new reality," in the Oxford outlook (1929); while continuing his literary interests, he worked for the U.S. government during World War II for the Office of War Information and also served as an interpreter for the State Department during the San Francisco conference which established the United Nations; published books include Poems for F (1934), Oscar Wilde: a critical study (1947), Dialogues on art (1960), De l'homosexualité (1962), In a lost world (1978), and Thrice chosen (1981); Roditi also held teaching positions at various colleges and universities; in addition to his literary achievements, Roditi was known as a generous and encouraging mentor to young writers; he died in Spain on May 10, 1992.
Chronology
1910 Born 6 June, Paris
1923 Attended Elstree School, Elstree, Herts, England
1923-1926 Attended Charterhouse, Godalming, England
1928-1929 Attended Balliol College, Oxford
1928 Partner in Editions du Sagittaire, publisher of early Surrealists
1928 In print at age 18, English translation of poems by Leon Paul Fargue published in Transition
1929 Published first Surrealist manifesto in English, "The New Reality," in the Oxford Outlook.
1929 First visited the United States at age 19
1929-1937 Lived in London, Paris, Berlin
1934 Roditi's poems published in Criterion
1934 Poems For F published
1937-1938 A.B. University of Chicago
1939 Fellowship, University of California, Berkeley
1940 Teacher, University of Kansas City, Missouri
1941 Prison Within Prison: Three Hebrew Elegies published
1941 Began work for the U.S. Government, Office of War Information, Radio Division
1942 Pieces Of Three published
1945 Interpreter for U.S. Department of State, San Francisco Conference, establishing the United Nations
1946-1951 Edited Das Lot, with Alain Bosquet and Alexander Koval
1946 Interpreter, Nuremburg International Military Tribunal
1947 Oscar Wilde: A Critical Study published
1948 Reports Officer & Governmental Administrator, Office of Military Government for Germany of the U.S.
1949 Poems 1928-1949 published
1950 Dismissed as alleged security risk by U.S. Government
1954 Established Paris residence
1958 Expelled from France for two years as an alleged security risk, expulsion order rescinded in 1960.
1960 Dialogues On Art published
1961 ER's English translation of Yashar Kemal's Memed, My Hawk published
1962 De L'homosexualite published
1962 Les Plus Belles Lettres D'eugene Delacroix selected, edited and published by ER
1966 Visiting professor, San Francisco State College. Anne Rice was one of his students.
1968 New Hieroglyphic Tales: Prose Poems published
1970 Visiting professor, University of California, Santa Cruz
1972 Magellan Of The Pacific published
1974 Emperor Of Midnight published
1975 The Disorderly Poet published
1977 Meetings With Conrad published, The Delights Of Turkey published
1978 In A Lost World published
1981 Thrice Chosen published, The Confessions Of A Saint published
1983 New Old & New Testaments published
1982 Etre Un Autre published
1984 More Dialogues On Art published
1985 ER's French translation of Horace Walpole's Hieroglyphic Tales published
1987 ER's English translation of The Wandering Fool, poems by 13th century Turkish Dervish Gurus, published
1987 Professor, Bard College, Annandale on Hudson
1987 Oscar Wilde reprinted
1989 Regents' Lecturer, University of California, Los Angeles
1992 Choose Your Own World published
1992 Died on May 10 in Cadiz, Spain
Scope and Content
Collection consists of material related to the life and career of surrealist author and poet Édouard Roditi. Includes correspondence, original and photocopied manuscripts by Roditi and others, books, periodicals and other printed items by or about Roditi, documents, awards, photographs, memorabilia, and letters regarding family history and biographical information, and books from his library, including many inscribed by artists and writers. Contains correspondence with various artists and literary figures including W.H. Auden, Paul Bowles, T.S. Eliot, Christopher Isherwood, Josef Herman, Ned Rorem, and Oskar Tauschinski. Also includes corrections made by Eliot to early poems ca. 1928-30 written by Roditi.
Organization and Arrangement
Arranged in the following series:
Correspondence.
Manuscripts by Édouard Roditi and others.
Printed material by or about Édouard Roditi.
Biographical and personal material.
Books from the library of Édouard Roditi.
Items Removed from Collection
Barbey d'Aureyvilly, J. (Jules). Laocoon. Los Angeles: William & Victoria Dailey, 1985. Introduction by Edouard Roditi (Special Collections call number: 1128454).
Breton, Andre. Young cherry trees secured against hares. [Ann Arbor]: University of Michigan Press, [c.1946]. Translations by Edouard Roditi (Special Collections call number: PQ 2603 B75 J5 1946).
Camoes, Luis de. Endechas a barbara. [Lisbon]: Isaac Holly, 1984. English translation by Edouard Copy no.173 of 250 (Special Colections call number: *PQ 9196 Z8 E 58 1984).
Eliasberg, Paul. Beim bau der Chinesischen Mauer. [California]: Ettan Press, 1975. Foreword by Edouard Roditi (Copy in Art Library: X3 163 105).
Goodman, Paul. Pieces of threee / Meyer Liben, Paul Goodman, Edouard Roditi (Beacon series). [Harrington, Park, New York: 5 x 8 Press, 1942] (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61pi).
Hamri, Mohamed. Tales of Joujouka. Santa Barbara, California: Capra Press, 1975. Guest editor: Edouard Roditi. Capra (Special Collections call number: GR 353.3 H3513).
Hernandez, Jose. Jose Hernandez-15 Fevrier-12 Mars 1977. Paris: Galerie Octave Negru, 1977[?] (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61jo).
Levi, Primo. Shema: Collected poems of Primo Levi. London: Menard Press, 1976. Introduction by Edouard Roditi (Special Collections call number: PS 509 B31 1976 L579s).
Picasso, Pablo. Toros y toreros. [New York]: H.N. Abrams, [1961] (Art Library: *NC 1135 P587D71E).
Schmutzler, Robert. Art nouveau. New York: H.M. Abrams, [c.1962]. English translation by Edouard Roditi (URL call number: *N 6494 N6535E).
Svevo, Italo. As a man grows older. [New York: New Directions, 1949?]. With an essay on Svevo by Edouard Roditi (URL call number: PQ 4841 S35S4E).
Waldemar-George. Hilaire Hiler and structuralism. New York: G. Wittenborn, [195-]. Translations by Edouard Roditi and Anna (Art Library call number: *ND 237 H547 W14).
Walpole, Horace. Contes hieroglyphiques. [Paris]: Librairie Jose Corti, 1985. Collection Romantique 12. Translated and with (Special Collections call number: 113693).
Yasar Kemal. Memed, my hawk. London: Collins and Harville Press, 1961. Translation by Edouard Roditi (URL call number: PL 250 Y22iE vol.1 1961).
Yasar Kemal. Memed, my hawk. New York: Pantheon Books, 1961. Translation by Edouard Roditi (Special Collections call number: 109200 ROD).
Yasar, Kemal. Memed, my hawk. New York: Pantheon Books, 1961. Translation by Edouard Roditi (URL call number: PL 250 Y22iE vol.1. 1961b).
Yunus Enre. The wandering fool: sufi poems of a thirteenth-century Turkish Dervish. Tiburon-Belvedere, California: Cadmus, 1986. Translated from the Turkish by Edouard Roditi & (Special Collections call number: 117316 ROD).
Anonymous songs by Greek-Jewish women prisoners in Auschwitz. Santa Rosa, California: Clamshell Press, 1984. Translated from the Modern Demotic Greek by, (Special Collections call number: *112937).
Wyndam Lewis et le vorticisme (Series: Cahiers pour un temps). [Clamecy]: Centre Georges Pompidou / Pandora Editions, 1982. With an essay, (Special Collections call number: 107728 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. Fabeltier. [Paris]: s.n. [1981]. Poem by Edouard Roditi, illustration by Caragaleiro. One of 250 signed by Roditi (See: ORION).
Roditi, Edouard. In erdnaehe. [Koeln: Verlag Galerie der Speiegel, 1960]. With original drawings by Heinz Troekes (See ORION, UCLA Library).
Roditi, Edouard. "William Harnett: American necromantic." In View (Series 5, no.4, pp.9, 19-20), November 1945 (No copy in collection. See Little Mag Collection 1000).
Roditi, Edouard. Oscar Wilde. New York: New Directions Publishing Corporation, 1986 (URL call number: PR 5824 R61o 1986).
Roditi, Edouard. Oscar Wilde: Dichter und Dandy. Munich: Verlag Herbert Kluger, 1947 (Clark Library call number: *PR 5823 R69G).
Roditi, Edouard. Meetings with Conrad. Los Angeles: Press of the Pegacycle Lady, 1977 (Clark Library call number: Press collection. Pegacycle Lady).
Roditi, Edouard. De l'homosexualite. Paris: Sedimo, 1962 (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61d).
Roditi, Edouard. The delights of Turkey. New York: New Directions Pub. Corporation, 1977 (URL call number: PS 3535 R61de).
Roditi, Edouard. The disorderly poet & other essays. Santa Barbara, California: Capra Press, 1975. Capra chapbook series no.29 (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61di).
Roditi, Edouard. New hieroglyphic tales. San Francisco: Kayak Books, c.1968. Drawings by Modesto Roldan (Special Collections call number: PS 509 B3R617n).
Roditi, Edouard. Magellano del Pacifico: La prima circumnavigazione del globo. [Milano]: Nursia, 1977 (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61nI 1977).
Roditi, Edouard. The temptations of a saint. [Rancho Santa Fe, California]: Ettan Press, 1980. Two original etchings by Jose (Clark Library call number: Press collection. Folio Reagh).
Roditi, Edouard. Oscar Wilde, Dichter und Dandy. Muenchen: H. Kluger, 1974 (Clark Library call number: *PR 5823 R69G).
Roditi, Edouard. Dialogues on art. New York: Horizon Press, [1961] (URL call number: ND 36 R61d).
Roditi, Edouard. In erdnaehe. Koeln: Galerie der Speigel, 1960 (Special Collections call number: *PS 3535 R61i).
Roditi, Edouard. Orphic love. New York: Hydra Group, 1986 (URL call number: PS 3535 R61o).
Roditi, Edouard. Thrice chosen. Santa Barbara: Black Sparrow Press, 1981 (URL call number: PS 3535 R61t).
Roditi, Edouard. Oscar Wilde. Norfolk, Connecticut: New Directions Books, [1947] (URL call number: PR 5824 R61o).
Roditi, Edouard. Poems, 1928-1948. Norfolk, Connecticut: New Directions Books, [1949] (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61A17).
Roditi, Edouard. Poems for F (Copy 132 of 250). Paris: Editions du Sagittaire, 1935 (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61po).
Roditi, Edouard. Prison within prison, three elegies on Hebrew themes. Prairie City, Ilinois: The Press of James A. Decker, 1941 (Special Collections call number: PS 3535 R61p).
Roditi, Edouard. Dialogues on art. Santa Barbara: Ross-Erikson, 1980 (Special Collections call number: 108495 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. Etre un autre. s.l.: s.n, 1982. Illustratiosn by Manuel Cargaleiro (Special Collections call number: *106871 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. More dialogues on art. Santa Barbara, California: Ross-Erikson, 1984 (Special Collections call number: 115074 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. New old & new testaments. New York: Red Ozier Press, 1983 (Special Collections call number: 108582 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. Orphic love. New York: Hydra Group, 1986 (Special Collections call number: 115889 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. Oscar Wilde. New York: New Directions Publishing Corporation, c.1986. New Directions paperbook 633. Enlarged and (Special Collections call number: 115794 ROD).
Roditi, Edouard. Oscar Wilde. Norfolk, Connecticut: New Directions Books [1947] (Special Collections call number: 104282).
Roditi, Edouard. Thrice chosen. Santa Barbara, California: Black Sparrow Press, 1981 (Special Collections call number: 105694 BSP, 3 copies).
Roditi, Edouard, interviewee. Inventions and imitations oral history transcript. [Los Angeles]: Oral History Program, UCLA, c.1986. Interview by Richard Candida Smith (Special Collections call number: 300/264).
Related Oral History
The following oral history is available through the UCLA Library Center for Oral History Research:
Inventions and imitations: tradition and the advanced guard in the work of Édouard Roditi [oral history transcript] / Édouard Roditi interviewee.
UCLA Oral History Department interview, 1985. Available at UCLA Library Special Collections, UCLA.
Poets, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Manuscripts for publication; Correspondence.; Authors, American -- 20th century -- Archives.; Roditi, Édouard--Archives.
- Correspondence.
  - Abramson, Samuel H., 1960. (Box 1)
  - Accent. A Quarterly of New Literature. Urbana, Ill., 1940-1946, undated (Box 1)
    Scope and Contents note
    Also: Quinn, Kerker
  - Achenbach Foundation for Graphic Arts. San Francisco., 1947-1974. (Box 1)
    Also: Kastner, Fenton; Troche, E. Gunter
  - Adam. Brighton., 1975. (Box 1)
    Also: Grindea, Miron
    Re Roditi's proposed article about his recollections of Cyril Connolly scheduled for publication in ADAM.
  - Adams, Walter R., 1940. (Box 1)
  - Adler, Jankel., 1933-1936. (Box 1)
  - Albahari, David., 1981. (Box 1)
  - Albright-Knox Art Gallery. Buffalo, N.Y., 1967. (Box 1)
    Also: West, Richard
    Re exhibition of Henry Valensi and ER's text for catalogue.
  - Alcalay, Ammiel., 1981-1985, undated (Box 1)
  - Alcatraz. Santa Cruz, Calif., 1983. (Box 1)
    Also: Kessler, Stephen
  - Aldington, Richard., 1940. (Box 1)
    Letter from Aldington to Roditi, Montego Bay, Jamaica, 20 July 1946. With news of the Aldingtons' move from Hollywood, and a report from Osbert Sitwell re postwar conditions in Switzerland and Italy.
  - Alessandri, Arturo B., 1973. (Box 1)
    Also: Roditi, Harold
    Letter to Harold Roditi regarding his brother Edouard's book, MAGELLAN OF THE PACIFIC.
  - Alexander, Edward., 1972-1978. (Box 1)
    Letter dated 7/22/72 has photocopy of letter from Edward Alexander to Alvin Rosenfeld, dated 7/1/1972.
  - Alexander, Sidney., 1979. (Box 1)
  - Alter, Robert., 1969. (Box 1)
  - Altrocchi, Professor R., 1939. (Box 1)
    Comments on an unidentified article by Edouard Roditi. With an additional note at the bottom of the page signed H.H.O.
  - Alyn, Marc., 1963. (Box 1)
  - Ambassador. St. Paul, Minn., 1978. (Box 1)
    Clippings from AMBASSADOR (v.11, no.10).; Morgan, James
  - American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters. New York., 1981-1982. (Box 1)
    Request for copies of Roditi's book, DIALOGUES ON ART, for consideration for a literary award, and request for a photograph for the awards announcement.
  - American Association of Language Specialists., 1982. (Box 1)
    Mid-year report.
  - American Book Review. New York., 1983. (Box 1)
    With typescript(carbon) of Roditi's letter, 12 September 1982, in response to criticism of his book, THRICE CHOSEN, which appeared in the August 1983 issue.
  - American Bookman. New York., 1944. (Box 1)
    Also: Shipley, Joseph
  - American Council of Learned Societies. Washington, D.C., 1949. (Box 1)
  - American Society for Aesthetics. Piedmont, Calif., 1942-1950. (Box 1)
    Also: Hungerland, Helmut; Munro, Thomas
  - Amerika Haus Bamberg. Bamberg, Germany., 1946. (Box 1)
    Also: Office of Military Government for Germany (U.S.)
    Letter of thanks to the Office of Military Government for Germany (U.S.) for Edouard Roditi's lecture, "Modern American poetry."
  - Andres, Stefan., 1948-1950. (Box 1)
  - Anger, Kenneth., 1951. (Box 1)
    Re Anger's proposed trip to Berlin to screen his film, Fireworks, for Dick Pohlandt.
  - Antaeus. The Ecco Press. New York., 1977, 1981, undated (Box 1)
    Also: Halpern, Daniel
  - Anti-Defamation League of B'nai B'rith. Chicago., 1940. (Box 1)
  - Antin, David., 1968, undated (Box 1)
  - Archivo Storico D'Arte Contemporanea. Venezia., 1953. (Box 1)
    Also: Apollonio, Umbro
    Regarding a special issue on Italo Svevo.
  - Argus Books, Inc. Mohegan Lake, New York., 1949-1950. (Box 1)
    Also: Abramson, Ben
  - Arizona Quarterly. Tucson, Ariz., 1945-1947. (Box 1)
  - Arnold, Fritz., 1981-1987. (Box 1)
  - Arrizabalaga y Prado, Leonardo de., 1976-1978, undated; [1 of 4 folders] (Box 1)
    3 letters undated.
  - Arrizabalaga y Prado, Leonardo de., 1980-1982.; [2 of 4 folders] (Box 1)
    With letter of 5/6/81, Arrizabalaga y Prado has enclosed an English translation of his poem, "Morning prayer."
  - Arrizabalaga y Prado, Leonardo de., 1982-1984.; [3 of 4 folders] (Box 1)
  - Arrizabalaga y Prado, Leonardo de., 1978-1985, undated; [4 of 4 folders] (Box 1)
  - Arslan, Yueksel., 1963-1985. (Box 1)
    3 letters are undated. Most letters have original sketches. Letter dated 1985 on back of photocopy of sketch of Edouard Roditi by Yueskel Arslan.
  - Art Institute of Chicago. Chicago, Ill., 1949. (Box 1)
  - Art International. Lugano, Switzerland., 1969. (Box 1)
  - Arte e Societa. Roma., 1973. (Box 1)
  - Arts in Society. University of Wisconsin. Madison., 1975. (Box 1)
    Also: Kamarck, Edward
  - Ashcroft, Dame Peggy., 1928-1983, undated (Box 1)
    l letter from Ashcroft is undated. Included is a copy of Roditi's letter to Ashcroft, Paris, 1 April 1983 and a photocopy of obituary for Edward Ashcroft, Peggy Ashcroft's brother. Roditi's notes indicate the relationship between Ashcroft and Roditi.
  - Ashraf, Princess., undated (Box 1)
    With Edouard Roditi's holograph note on envelope, "Invitation to Imperial reception in palace of Princess Ashraf, Tehren."
  - Associated Research Councils. Washington, D.C., 1950. (Box 1)
  - Atlanta University. Trevor Arnett Library. Atlanta, Georgia., 1974-1980. (Box 1)
  - Atlanta University. Wallace Van Jackson Library. Atlanta, Georgia., 1944-1948. (Box 1)
  - Atlantic Monthly. Boston, Mass., 1945-1950. (Box 1)
    Also: Rolo, Charles; Weeks, Edward
  - Aubray, Therese., undated (Box 1)
  - Auric, Georges., 1960. (Box 1)
  - Aury, Dominique., 1953-1966. (Box 1)
    Also: Nouvelle Revue Francaise. Paris.
  - Auster, Paul., 1980. (Box 1)
    Re Auster's proposed anthology of modern French poetry.
  - Bachem, Bele., 1966-1983. (Box 1)
    Many of these letters have original sketches by Bachem.
  - Bader, K., 1974. (Box 1)
  - Bak, Robert C., 1949. (Box 1)
  - Baker, Mark Allen., 1982. (Box 1)
  - Balakian, Anna., 1970-1987. (Box 1)
    Re proposed collaborative publications on Surrealism and Symbolist movement.
  - Ballard, Jean., 1930-1933, undated; [1 of 2 folders] (Box 1)
    Enclosed is a typescript(carbon) copy of a 2 page proposed table of contents for a special issue of Cahiers du Sud with holograph additions on page 1 by Balllard.; Cahiers du Sud. Marseilles.
    3 letters and the enclosure are undated.
  - Ballard, Jean., 1935-1941.; [2 of 2 folders] (Box 1)
    Also: Cahiers du Sud. Marseilles.
  - Balliol College. Oxford., 1983-1985. (Box 1)
  - Bandler, Bernard., 1929. (Box 1)
    Also: Hound & Horn. Cambridge, Mass.
  - Barnstone, Willis., undated (Box 1)
  - Baron, Todd., 1982, 1983, undated (Box 1)
    Baron's letter of 2/15/82 encloses a statement of purpose for the poetry journal, Issue. Letter dated 12/1/83 has copy of Todd Baron's poem "Pigeon hole".; Issue. Los Angeles.
    4 letters are undated. Included in the correspondence are typescript(carbon) copies of Roditi's letters 3/8/83 and 8/23/83.
  - Barzun, Jacques., 1952-1953. (Box 1)
    Re Roditi's translations of some of Barzun's works. Copies of Roditi's letters to Barzun are included.
  - Bassani, Giorgio., 1952-1963. (Box 1)
    Included are 3 copies of Roditi's letters to Bassani.
  - Bauschinger, Sigrid., 1980. (Box 1)
  - Baxter, Iain., undated (Box 1)
  - Bay, Andre., 1969-1970. (Box 1)
    Also: Editions Stock. Paris.
  - Bazlen, Roberto., 1954. (Box 1)
  - Beach, Sylvia., 1929. (Box 1)
    Also: Shakespeare and Company. Paris.
    Re Roditi's unnamed article on James Joyce and a proposed article on "Work in Progress."
  - Bearden, Romare., 1948. (Box 1)
    Authorization for reproductions of Bearden's paintings in the magazine ULENSPIEGEL.
  - Bedou, Dominique., 1979. (Box 1)
  - Behmer, Marcus., 1957. (Box 1)
  - Belgian Press Association, Inc. New York., 23 April 1941. (Box 1)
  - Bellmer, Hans., 1959. (Box 1)
  - Ben Gurion University of the Negev. Beersheva, Israel., 1980. (Box 1)
  - Benezra, Moiz., 1983. (Box 1)
  - Benn, Gottfired., 1950. (Box 1)
  - Bension, Ida., undated (Box 1)
    Re Roditi's unfavorable review of her husband's book.
  - Bentley, Eric., 1950, undated (Box 1)
  - Bergengruen, Werner., 26 July 1950. (Box 1)
  - Berger, Arthur., 1951. (Box 1)
  - Bergner, Yosl., 1976. (Box 1)
  - Berlin Museum. Berlin., 1978-1980. (Box 2)
    Also: Wirth, Irmgard
    Enclosed with letter of 1/3/80 are a pamphlet for "Erwerbungen und Stiftungen fuer das kuenftige Juedische Museum seit Herbst 1978," an invitation, and a card with information about the meeting.
  - Berlin, Isaiah., 1930. (Box 2)
  - Berman, Eugene., 1967-68. (Box 2)
  - Bermann-Fischer / Querido Verlag. Amsterdam., 1949-1950. (Box 2)
    Enclosed with letter of September 1949 is a list of books by Klaus Mann.
    Also: Landshoff, F. H.
    Re Edouard Roditi's contribution to a book on Klaus Mann.
  - Bernheim, Jeune et Cie., undated (Box 2)
  - Bernheim, Mark., 1981, undated (Box 2)
    Re Edouard Roditi's introduction to the Other Languages section of VOICES WITHIN THE ARK and Mark Bernheim's review of the anthology for the JEWISH SPECTATOR.
  - Bertele, Rene., 1971. (Box 2)
    Also: Editions Gallimard. Paris.
  - Bertin, Gabriel., 1938, undated (Box 2)
  - Bessiere, Jean., 1981. (Box 2)
    Letter of thanks from Jean Bessiere to participants of Colloque Larbaud, a colloquium on Valery Larbaud.
  - Betjeman, John. (Box 2)
    Also: Architectural Review. Westminster, England.
  - Bezirksamt Charlottenburg von Gross-Berlin. Berlin., 1949-1950. (Box 2)
    Re Edouard Roditi's lecture at an event concerning "Goethe im Urteil des Auslandes." Typescript (carbon) of Roditi's letter, 10/3/49, in response to a speaking engagement at this event.
  - Bien, Peter., 1963. (Box 2)
    Re Requesting a permission to quote from Edouard Roditi's article,"Cavafis and the Permanence of Greek History."
  - Birmingham, Stephen. (Box 2)